<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Adventure Game</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>
    <string name="intro">One dark spooky night, you and your friends James and John are playing truth or dare. When it comes to be your turn you choose dare. “I dare you to go into the spooky graveyard across the street!” says James. Not wanting to look like a chicken, you agree. So you walk across the street to the graveyard, while James, and John stand in front of John’s house on the other side. In your way is an imposing iron gate.</string>
    <string name="loose">James and John laugh at you. They call you the biggest chicken of all time. In your shame you become depressed and you fail all your classes, especially OOP. \nTHE END</string>
    <string name="yes">Open the gate.</string>
    <string name="no">Chicken out.</string>
    <string name="try_again">Try Again</string>
    <string name="nothing">null</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main3">Main3Activity</string>
    <string name="court_yard">You put your hand on the iron wrought gate and push, the doors make a sharpened screech as you cross the threshold into the graveyard. You walk a few steps in, but then get a shiver down your spine. You decide that has been enough adventuring for one day and turn back to leave, only for there to be a sharp cold wind, and the deafening sound of the gate slamming behind you. Frightened, you run back to the gate, pulling on it with all of your might, but to no avail, it is sealed shut. You notice a keyhole in the gate and start searching for a key. The clouds part and you see a mysterious decrepit house on the hill. </string>
    <string name="cont">Continue…</string>
    <string name="court_yard2"> As you head up to the house you walk through the graveyard you were dared to go through. You are a little worried because of the entire series of events, but graveyards don’t scare you, after all, they’re just corpes in the ground, they can’t hurt you. You continue to walk around the graveyard, observing the epithets that are carved into the ancient headstones. One that gives you a good chuckle reads: “Dear Departed brother Dave, he chased a bear into a cave.” Laughter is the best medicine after all, you feel slightly more at ease.</string>
    <string name="cy_opt1">Continue exploring the graveyard.</string>
    <string name="cy_opt2">Go up to the front porch of the house.</string>
    <string name="porch">You walk up the rickety, decayed stairs to the front door. You walk forward to the giant imposing wooden door. You decide to be polite and knock to see if anyone is of residence. You give three hard knocks on the door and hear them echo through the hallowed halls within. You wait a while, but there is no answer. You decide to be forceful and let yourself in. You try to turn the doorknob but to no avail. Seems like the door is locked. Better find a key to use.</string>
    <string name="gy_cont"> You continue searching for the graveyard, hoping that maybe the key is somewhere around these graves…</string>
    <string name="gy_cont2"> All of a sudden you hear a rattling sound. You look around, maybe there’s a dog? But no. Around a crypt creeps a skeleton. You are shocked beyond all belief to see this re-animated corpse. It’s skin and muscle completely gone, save for the walking bones. You are frozen in fear, you cannot move to run away. You hear more rattling around you, you are surrounded by these gutless corpses. </string>
    <string name="gy_cont_opt1">Try talking to them.</string>
    <string name="talk">You try talking to the skeletons, seeing if you can reason with them. You tell them you are just lost and need to leave through the gate. There is no physical response. What do you do now?</string>
    <string name="gy_cont_opt2">Tell skeleton jokes.</string>
    <string name="joke1"> You do the only thing that comes to mind, you tell a joke. After all, laughter is the best medicine, and if you want to save your sanity you need to do something to calm you down? Right? So you let one of your best skeleton jokes rip. “Do you guys want to hear a skeleton joke?” you blurt out. The skeletons stop coming towards you and stare at you with their empty sockets. So you decide to deliver the punch line: “Never mind! I don’t have the guts to tell one!”</string>
    <string name="joke2"> The skeletons back away a little, look from one to the other, and look disturbed if that was at all possible without any facial muscles. You feel better, so you decide to tell another one “How did the skeletons deliver their mail in the olden days? By boney-express!” The skeletons begin to back away from you so you decide to hit them with one more joke: “What did the skeleton say while lining his Harley Davidson? I’m bone to be wild!”</string>
    <string name="joke3"> The skeletons, obviously completely put off by your bad jokes, run off over the moor, to where you can only hear the trousle of bones in the distance. A glimmer catches your eye, you look down and see a key shaped like a skeleton, one could even call it a skeleton key? You decide to hold onto it and put it in your backpack.</string>
    <string name="gy_cont_opt3">Try fighting them.</string>
    <string name="fight">You become so afraid you start trying to attack the stack of bones, but to no avail. Bone is stronger than concrete afterall, but you’re too afraid to know or care. You end up hurting your hand, and as the skeletons get even closer to you, you realize you can’t fight them all. So you crouch down and crawl through their femurs and run around them. They realize where you went and start walking towards you once again. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_foyer">Foyer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_grave_yard">GraveYard</string>
    <string name="gate">You run back to the gate. It is still sealed shut. You try and put the skeleton keyhole in the gates key hole. It doesn’t fit. You figure someone in the house must have the key or at least help you get out, so you set off to the house.</string>
    <string name="go_gate">Use the skeleton key on the gate.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gate">Gate</string>
    <string name="title_activity_porch">Porch</string>
    <string name="open_door">You walk up the rickety, decayed stairs to the front door. You walk forward to the giant imposing wooden door and put the key into the lock. The skeleton key worked! However it got caught in the keyhole and you cannot pull it out, probably best to leave it there, it’s not as if anyone else will be needing it.</string>
    <string name="open_door_fail">You walk up the rickety, decayed stairs to the front door. You walk forward to the giant imposing wooden door. You decide to be polite and knock to see if anyone is of residence. You give three hard knocks on the door and hear them echo through the hallowed halls within. You wait a while, but there is no answer. You decide to be forceful and let yourself in. You try to turn the doorknob but to no avail. Seems like the door is locked. Better find a key to use.</string>
    <string name="look_for_key">Go back to the graveyard to find a key.</string>
<!--    foyer-->
    <string name="foyer">As you enter the dark ominous house you can barely see anything except what is illuminated by the moon. As you walk in the door closes behind you. You think to yourself you should do something to prop these doors open in the future. You reach for the doorknob only to find that it is not locked! Makes things easier for you, you suppose. You turn back to the foyeye and start to walk around, only for hundreds of candles to be lit simultaneously. The room is lit up so you can see a few doors in front of you. You choose one. </string>
    <string name="door1">Grandiose door with music playing behind it.</string>
    <string name="door2">A normal looking door with clamoring sounds behind it.</string>
    <string name="door3">A stair case that is visibly blocked by furniture.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dining">Dining</string>
    <string name="k_locked">The normal looking door is locked.</string>
<!--    dinging-->
    <string name="s_blocked">You can\'t get passed all the furniture, and it is all too heavy to move.</string>
    <string name="dining">You go up to the grandiose doors and push them open. Once inside the room you hear swelling organ music, and you see a giant organ, however you do not see anyone playing it. There is a long dining table in the center of the room with mountains of food, silverware and a few other items on it.</string>
    <string name="dining2">You enter the dining room again. The ghosts are still twirling around the room. There is a long dining table in the center of the room with mountains of food, silverware and a few other items on it.</string>
    <string name="to_door">Try to go through the door. </string>
    <string name="ex_items">Go check out the items on the table. </string>
    <string name="wo_glasses">You try to make your way to the door, but you are constantly pushed back to the entrance by an invisible force. No matter how hard you try you cannot cross the room.</string>
<!--   TABLE-->
    <string name="w_glasses"> As you put the glasses on you see misty almost transparent specters. They are eating jovily and dancing to the music. You notice another specter passionately playing the organ. You slip through the dancing and celebrating spirits, who either don’t notice or don’t care about your presence. It doesn’t matter either way, you get to the door and open it.</string>
    <string name="check_table"> Surly something on this table can help you, what will you grab? </string>
    <string name="goblet">A Goblet filled with a red liquid.</string>
    <string name="glasses">A pair of eyeglasses.</string>
    <string name="book">An old looking book.</string>
    <string name="af_goblet">You pick up the goblet, you try to figure out what is in the cup, but you can\'t. Do you drink it?</string>
    <string name="drink">Bottoms up.</string>
    <string name="af_drink">...it tasts like...fruit punch?</string>
    <string name="table">Look at the table again.</string>
    <string name="put_back">Put it back on the table.</string>
    <string name="hold_on">Hold on to it for later.</string>
    <string name="af_glasses">You pick up the glasses, they look pretty old. </string>
    <string name="put_on">Put them on. </string>
    <string name="af_book">You pick up the book and open it, but it isn\'t written in english. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_table">Table</string>
    <string name="go_door">Go through the door.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_kitchen">Kitchen</string>
<!--KITCHEN-->
    <string name="k_enter">As you open the door you realize you walked into a giant kitchen filled with herbs hanging off shelves, food spilling out of every cabinet. There are newt toes, rat tails, eyeballs in jars. You see a giant black cauldron with boiling green and purple liquid inside. You see a figure come out from the lines of shelves. She had skin that was tinted green, wore a long black dress, and had a black pointed hat. It was a witch! You begin to back up before she can turn you into a ferret, or steal your life force, or something witches do! As you back up your back hit a cabinet and knock a jar with some crystals over. You stand frozen, you don’t want to move a muscle. She looks up at you and begins cackling over the cauldron.</string>
    <string name="k_option1">Run back to the door.</string>
    <string name="k_option2">Knock over her cauldron. </string>
    <string name="k_option3">Throw something at her. </string>
    <string name="k_option1_2">You run back towards the door, however you feel your body transform. You look down at yourself and realize you have been turned into a toad! The witch floats you over to her and turns you back into your normal human self. You are right back where you started.</string>
    <string name="k_option2_2">You decide to try and fight her. You have no idea what’s in this cauldron, but it can’t be good. You run to it and tilt it so the bubbling liquid spills over her. The witch begins screaming in agony, you see some sort of energy running through her body. You begin to back away, but before you can get too far, she zaps you with lightning. You yell out in pain and run towards the door. You make it back out to the dining room, a little singed but otherwise ok. </string>
    <string name="k_option3_2">You pick up the crystal and throw it, and as it hits her, a black cloud of smoke seeped out of her body and entered the crystal. The witch said “You removed the curse that was placed upon me. You see I was cursed to cackle for the rest of eternity, but you broke the spell, and now I am indebted to you.” You explain that you just want to leave, but the gate is locked so you cannot go. The witch responds, “I don’t have the key to the gate, but I assume the master of the house does. He is cooped up in his bedroom upstairs, Perhaps you can try and talk to him.” You explain to Hazel that you cannot get upstairs because there is furniture blocking the way. “Furniture huh? Those pesky spirits must be playing their pranks again. Well, I have a decluttering spell I could use, it is in my spell book… but I can’t remember where I left it...</string>
    <string name="use_book"> Give her the book you found. </string>
    <string name="look_book">Go look for the book. </string>
    <string name="af_give_book">“Ahh! Fantastic,  just the book I need!” Hazel begins to move around grabbing ingredients and throwing them into her cauldron. She says a few words and the potion turns many different colors. Pretty soon she is scooping the now-turned-purple liquid into a glass flask and hands it to you. “Now, when you get back into the entryway, throw this potion onto the furniture and it should declutter itself! Now if there is anything else you need help with or need me to do! Don’t hesitate to come ask me!” You thank Hazel once again and set out to leave the kitchen.</string>
    <string name="k_enter_after">The witch sees you enter and says, "Welcome back, did you find my book?"</string>
    <string name="no_book">Tell her no, and keep looking. </string>
    <string name="exit_k">Leave the kitchen.</string>
    <string name="tbd">Next Update Coming soon!</string>
    <string name="play_again">Start Over</string>
</resources>
